Fran?
我是Robi
I'm robi
请进
Please,come in.
屋子真可爱
cute home.
两个卧室 一个浴室?
Two bedroom,one bath?
是的
Yeah.
我认识个人收集这些玩意儿
A guy I know collects those.
说在互联网上能卖一大笔钱
He says they're worth,a fortune on the internet.
是的
Yeah.
你从没使用过我们的服务吧?
You've never used our agency before,,have you?
这么显而易见?
Is it that obvious?
我们提供全面周到的服务
As you can see,,we offer a full range of services.
"环游世界"?
"Round the world"?
我们的豪华套餐提供a b c所含的全部服务
Our deluxe package offers,all the services of a,b,and C.
多少钱?
How much?
1千美金
$1,000.
保证让你满意
And satisfaction's guaranteed.
两次
Twice.
我去取钱
I'll get the money.
我去准备
I'll get ready.
Harrington?
Harrington.
Harrington
你在上面干什么?
What are you doing up there?
好吧 现在
All right,now.
别往心里去 但你得离...
Don't take this personally,,but you're gonna have to go—
Fran?
这样行吗?
Is this okay?
Fran?
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
哦 我的天
Oh,god.
Fran?
是的...北枫街500号需要救护车
Yeah,I--,I need an ambulance at 500 north sycamore.
我不知道
I don't know.
我的...朋友晕倒了
My...friend collapsed.
-=怪杰医生豪斯=-,第三季 第18集,"空载"; "Airborne"
House,Season 03 Episode 18
你昏倒时 在干什么?
and what were you doing when you fainted?
我们只是...
We were just--
在找她的猫
looking for her cat.
最近撞到过脑袋吗?
And have you banged your head recently?
没有
No.
这是抗运动病贴片吗?,(防止运动异常引起的神经系统失调)
Is this a motion sickness patch?
我一定忘了把它取下来
I must've forgotten to take it off.
我刚旅行回来
I just got back from a trip.
哦
Oops.
东莨菪碱(镇静剂)可以引起头昏眼花
Scopolamine can cause,dizziness and blurred vision.
你跌倒的时候一定脑袋撞地
You probably hit your head,when you fell
所以会失去知觉
and that caused the blackout.
我以为贴片是为了预防不适
I thought those patches were supposed,to prevent you from getting sick.
药物皆有副作用
Every drug has a side effect.
接下来几个小时 你最好能照看她
But it might be a good idea,to keep your eye on her
确保她安然无恙
for the next few hours,to make sure she's okay.
实际上 我...
Oh,actually I--
她得回去工作
she has to get back to work.
这很重要吗?
Is it important?
只是不希望人们出院后一个人待着
We just don't like people to be alone,after they leave here.
我没事的
I'm fine.
真的 我
Really,I'm-- I'm--
Fran?
Fr-Fran?
有病人抽搐 急救小车!
I got a seizure. Code cart!
她怎么了?
What's wrong with her?
我不知道
I have no idea.
House在哪儿?
Where's house?
葡萄酒商的古董拐杖
Antique vintner's cane.
花了我900美金
It cost me $900.
里面有个开塞钻,(不可随身携带上飞机)
It had a corkscrew in it.
所以才叫"葡萄酒商"的
Ah,that would explain,the "vintner's" reference.
可以用来攻击飞行员
Could be used as a weapon,against the pilot.
用来开启馨芳葡萄酒罢了
Only if you stuck it,in a bottle of zinfandel.
一下飞机你就可以拿回来
You'll get it back when we land.
我要毯子!我要毯子!
I want my blankie!,I want my blankie!
给她注射20毫升抗组胺剂
Give her 20 milligrams of antihistamine.
可以救她一命
It could save her life.
因为如果她不闭嘴 我就会痛下杀手
Cause if she doesn't shut up,,I'll kill her.
向另一个大陆传达你的美意
delivering good,will to yet another continent.
你只逼我发表演讲 而不是传达美意
You only forced me to deliver a speech,,not good will.
你只演讲了三分钟
You gave a three-minute speech.
知道世界卫生组织的鉴定,对医院多重要吗?
You know how much,WHO accreditation means to the hospital?
发言也许很短 但有广度
May have been short,,but it had girth.
你恶意使用客房服务
And the room service thing,was just spiteful.
我饿了
I was hungry.
- 300美金一瓶的葡萄酒,- 我渴了
- $300 for a bottle of wine.,- Was thirstY.
120美金的付费电视
$120 on video services.
我孤独
I was lonely.
总共500美金的不合理消费
That's $500 in expenses,I can't justify.
别担心 我会搞定的
Don't worry.,I'll take care of it.
好吧
Right.
给您 先生
Here you are,sir.
欢迎登机
Welcome aboard.
House先生 您的座位就在这儿 2a
Mr. House,you're right here in 2a.
Cuddy女士 您在后面舱位的左侧 9c
Ms. Cuddy,you're in the next cabin,and to the left,9c.
不对 我预定了两张头等舱机票
No,I booked two first-class tickets.
这一定是弄错了
This must be a mistake.
没弄错
No mistake.
在机票费上缩减了500美金
Just arranged for a $500 fare reduction.
开支问题解决了
Expense problem solved.
你去哪儿旅行了?
Where did you travel?
德卢斯 (在明尼苏达州东北部)
Duluth.
去探望我妹妹
To visity sister.
真的?
Really?
这是她的艺术作品?
Is this her artwork?
惹火...屁股?
fire...butt?
我那时有点醉了
I was a little drunk.
你在哪儿喝醉了?
Where were you a little drunk?
今年三月 我58岁了
I turned 58 last march.
跟我妈死时的年纪一样
Same age my mother was,when she died.
第二个星期我打了个包
Next week I packed a bag.
奔向肯尼迪机场
I went to jfk.
看着巨大的航班指示牌
Looked at the big board.
搭乘开往温暖地带的第一班航班
Took the first plane,that went to a warm place.
加拉加斯 (委内瑞拉首都)
Caracas.
哦 我的天哪
Oh,my god.
你喝那儿的水了?
Did you drink the water?
吃色拉了 吃生食了?
Eat salads? Any raw foods?
没错
Yup.
还有呢?
And?
我注射龙舌兰致幻剂
I also did mescal shooters,
从同性恋男人的肚皮上吸食可卡因
and snorted cocaine from,a homosexual man's stomach.
你做爱了吗?
Did you have sex?
没有
No.
没跟他做
Not with him.
我跟个大胖子做爱了
I had sex with el gordo.
他个子很大
He was a large man.
我的天
Oh,my god.
我从不离经叛道
I never do things like that.
我本该去探望我妹妹
I should have gone to visit my sister.
这真够蠢的
It was stupid.
我是因为这个才病的 对吗?
That's why I'm sick,isn't it?
呃...
Uh...
这...有可能
it's...possible.
给您 三至四分熟的牛腓利
Here you are.,Rib eye,medium rare.
谢谢
Thank you.
要再来点灰皮诺葡萄酒吗?
Some more pinot grigio?
不用了
Uh,no.
我改喝席拉葡萄酒好了
I think I will switch to the syrah.
先生 你没事吧?
Sir,are you all right?
他喝醉了
He's drunk.
看见没?
See?
[韩语] 先生 你还好吧?
[korean]***
[韩语] 我 没什么
有人会说韩语吗?
Does anyone speak korean?
有谁是医生吗?
Is anyone a doctor?
有
Yes.
我去把她叫来
I'll go get her.
你想干什么?
What do you want?
真以为我忍心让你在后面挤上18个小时?
Did you really think I was gonna leave you,stuck back here for 18 hours?
去吧 尽情享受
Go on. Enjoy.
有了维柯丁和葡萄酒
The vicodin and the wine.
我哪都能睡
I could sleep anywhere.
谢谢
Thank you.
应该继续让她用东莨菪碱贴片
we should put her back,on the scopolamine patch.
她不能再贴抗运动病贴片了
She can't wear motion sickness patches,for the rest of her life.
是不能 但如果这能减轻症状,就可以缩小查找范围
no,but if it does relieve her symptoms,,it'll narrow down our search.
你俩还有什么意见一致?
Ugh,anything else,you two guys want to agree on?
我们意见一致让你很不爽吗?
You have a problem with us agreeing?
没有 你们干的其它事让我不爽
no,I have a problem with,the other thing you're doing
怀疑你们意见一致有动机
which makes me question,your motive for agreeing.
继续给她用贴片
I'll put her backon the patch.
还有别的吗?
What else?
应该是神经上的病症
It's got to be something neurological.
该做CT 检查是否有脑瘤
We should do a ct and,look for a brain tumor.
也可能是敏感症或跟环境有关
It can also be an allergy or,something environmental.
该去她家查查
We should check her home.
她更可能是在加拉加斯,而不是在新泽西染的病
Bit more likely she got sick in caracas,than in new jersey.
好吧 我忘了美国没有毒素
Right,,I forgot there are no toxins in the U.S.
我开始同情起House来了
I think I'm starting to feel sorry for house.
进行毒理筛检 血清生化检查,性病检查 血液培养
Get a tox screen,chem 20,std panel,,blood cultures,
你去做CT 你去查她家里
then you run a ct,,and you check her house.
拜托了
Please.
不好笑
Not funny.
本来就不好笑 哈哈
Wasn't supposed to be funny "ha ha."
高烧 头疼 腹部剧痛
Fever,headache,severe abdominal pain,,and a rash
下背部长满皮疹
all over his lower back.
很严重
It's serious.
很可能会传染
It may be contagious.
我们刚参加完一个传染病讨论会
We just attended a symposium,on pandemics
就让你在返程航班上碰到一个
and you run right into one,on the flight home.
世界真小啊
Talk about a small world.
如果是脑膜炎球菌 飞机上可能一半乘客
If it's meningococcus,,half the passengers on this plane
会在抵达纽约前受感染死亡
could get infected,and die before we reach new york.
有人生病了吗?
Is someone sick?
没有
No.
有人宿醉
Someone has a hangover.
餐前饮血玛丽酒过度
He had a snoot-load of bloody,marys before dinner.
看你的电影
Watch the movie.
皮疹不是酒引起的
That booze did not give him the rash.
是典型的脑脊膜炎症
It is textbook meningococcus.
也是典型的花粉过敏 花生过敏
It's also textbook allergic reaction,to pollen,peanuts,
躺在沾有精液的涤纶毯上发生的过敏
semen-stained polyester blanket,he's lying on.
Peng先生又呕吐了
Mr. Peng's throwing up again.
我们得调头回去
We have to turn around.
什么?
What?
- 为什么要调...,- 我们不用
- Why do we have to turn ar--?,- We don'T.
你误解了
You misunderstood.
Cuddy医生是说 如果他
Dr. Cuddy just meant that,he might feel less nauseous
朝着反方向 就不那么容易犯恶心了
if he was facing in,a different direction.
她不想引起机上全体人员的恐慌
She didn't mean to,panica plane load of people.
我们正飞向北极上空
We're about to head over the north pole.
如果现在我们不掉头,要等15个小时后才有急诊
We don't turn back now,,the next er's 15 hours away.
他会没事的
He'll be fine.
我也是医生
I'm a doctor too.
你还没替他做过检查
You haven't examined him.
韩国男性 30多岁,5英尺9英寸 体重160磅 秃顶
Korean male, mid-thirties, 5'9, 160, bald,
右下颚有疤痕
scar on the rightside of his jaw,
左手腕戴有医学警示手镯,(提示佩戴人的身体状况)
medic alert bracelet on his left wrist
表明他至少对青霉素过敏
indicating that he is allergic to at least,,penicillin.
没法验血 不能排除脑膜炎球菌
Without any way to do an lp,,or rule out meningococcus,
唯一的选择就是做最坏的假设
our only choice is to assume the worst.
言之有理
Good point.
另一方面
On the other hand,
我是管理委员会认定的传染病专家
I ama board certified specialist,in infectious disease.
她只负责分配停车位
She assigns parking spaces.
如果他情况恶化 麻烦通知我
Please let me know if he gets any worse.
该喂猫吃点东西吗?
Think we should feed the cat?
盆是满的
Bowl's full.
他想吃就会吃的
If he wants it,he can get it.
镉黄(颜料)
Cadmium yellow?
重金属中毒可以解释共济失调和抽搐
Heavy metal poisoning would explain,the ataxia and the seizures.
除非她用舌头画画
Not unless she was painting with her tongue.
Foreman说得对吗?
Is Foreman right?
你因为我们交往而同意我的说法?
Did you agree with me,because of our relationship?
交往?
Relationship?
我知道我指什么
You know what I mean.
你指我们关系不确定?
You mean because of,our lack of a relationship?
我指我们有性关系
I mean because we're having sex.
对 Foreman说得对
Yes,Foreman's right.
我觉得你想这么用药完全错
I thought you were completely wrong,about the medicine,
但我还是同意你
but agreed with you anyway,
因为我觉得这样,你就会在某个老妇人家里干我
because I figured then you'd do,mein some old lady's home.
演得真像
Then well played.
得了吧 我们是来找毒素的
Come on,we're supposed,to be looking for toxins.
我们都同意这是个脑瘤
We agreed it was a brain tumor.
什么?
What?
他在看
He's watching.
以前没让人看过吗?
Haven't you had any body watch before?
那家伙真的病了?
Is that guy really sick?
不 他完全好转了
No,he's all better.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
看那边
Look that way.
为什么?
Why?
因为你要吐了 我不想你吐我一身
Cae you're gonna throw up,and I don't want it on me.
我去拿毛巾
I'll get some towels.
给她个香蕉
Give her a banana.
猴子看见吐 就学着吐
Monkey see, monkey barf.
你嗅到呕吐的味道...
You smell vomit--
好吧
okay.
这我没料到...
I wasn't expecting that.
我需要帮手
I need help.
谁不需要?
Who doesn't?
我需要有人听我说话
I need someone to talk to.
你说说看...
Can you say...
"唉呀 哥们儿"?(澳洲口音)
"crikey, mate"?
唉呀 哥们儿
Crikey, mate.
好极了
Perfect.
不管我说什么 你都同意 好吗?
No matter what I say,,you agree with me,okay?
好...吧
O-kay.
干得漂亮
Nicely done.
你...不管我说什么都反对
You disagree with everything I say.
抱歉
Sorry.
我听不懂
Not understanding.
那也差不多
That's close enough.
而你...
And you...
不管我说什么 都正直地表示抗议
get morally outraged at everything I say.
那是不可擦除的记号笔 知道吗?
That's permanent marker,you know?
你们可真不错
You guys are good.
寻找这些症状最简单的解释
We are looking for the simplest way,to explain these symptoms.
有机磷酸酯中毒
Organophosphate poisoning.
某种跨国航班上使用的喷雾杀虫剂
Some international flights spray pesticides.
呃...有可能
Uh, could be.
抱歉 英文不太好
Sorry, english not so nice.
开什么玩笑?
Is this a joke?
已经飞出一半路程
Just passed the halfway mark.
不能回头了
Can't turn around.
- 是你高明的决定,- 不用客气
- Nice call. - No worries.
我们认为是杀虫剂中毒
We think it's pesticide poisoning.
这些航班上没有用过
We don't spray these flights.
晕海宁过量服用
Dramamine overdose.
解释不了发热症状
wouldn't explain the fever.
倒时差
jet lag.
解释不了腹部疼痛
Wouldn't explain the abdominal pain.
深度静脉血栓
Deep vein thrombosis.
解释不了晕吐
wouldn't explain the nausea.
食物中毒
Food poisoning.
菜单上有什么?
What was on the menu?
头等舱是牛排和蒸鳕鱼
Steak and sea bass in first class.
经济舱是意粉和烤海鲜串
Fettuccini and seafood kebabs in economy.
什么时候食物也能导致皮疹了?
Since when does food poisoning cause a rash?
蒸鳕鱼 烤海鲜串?
Sea bass,seafood kebabs?
他吃的是蒸鳕鱼
He had the sea bass.
请务必告诉我她吃的是烤海鲜串
Please tell me she had the kebabs.
我想是的
I think so.
鱼肉中毒
Ciguatera poisoning.
这是当场发作的毒素
It's an instant onset toxin.
这里写的全部症状都包括
Symptoms include'e' all of the above.
只存于几种供垂钓的热带鱼类中 比如...
It's only found in certain kinds of,tropical gamefish such as...
鳕鱼?
sea bass?
记得问他要份简历
Make sure you get a resume from him.
你们好
Hello.
不好意思
Excuse me.
女生们先生们
ladies and gentlemen,
我有一个关于你们用餐的简要通报
I have a brief announcement,concerning your meals.
如果你们食用了蒸鳕鱼或者烤海鲜串
If you ate the sea bass,or the seafood kebabs,
那你们已摄入一种危险毒素
you have ingested a dangerous toxin.
但是 若你们去位于机尾两侧的...
However,if you proceed to the restrooms,
洗手间尽快吐出
both on your left and right and in the rear of,the plane and vomit as soon as possible,
毒素作用将会降到最低
the toxic effect should be minimal.
谢谢你们 并祝旅途愉快
Thank you and havea pleasant flight.
脑膜炎球菌也能解释通
Meningococcus makes just as much sense.
我知道
I know.
找到什么?
What'd you find?
她房子里找不到什么
Nothing in her house.
完全是浪费时间
Big waste of time.
从医学角度来说
Medically.
CT也是白费
Ct was a complete waste.
她没有肿瘤
She was negative for tumors,
血检也没发现毒品或重金属
her blood was negative for drugs,,heavy metals,
热带病 食物中毒或者性病
tropical diseases,food poisoning,and stds.
也没有铅中毒或者脓毒病的征兆
Also no signof lead poisoning or sepsis.
看来委内瑞拉的纹身小店也讲卫生标准
Apparently, venezuelan tattoo parlors,have standards after all.
多谢告知
Good to know.
我们确定她有病?
We sure she's even sick?
两小时里又有两次癫痫发作
Two more seizures in the last two hours.
比你给她贴上贴片前要减缓了
Which is slower than she was having them,before you put the patch back on.
我真是个傻瓜
I'm an idiot.
她接触了这么多脏东西
She's exposed herself to so much crap,
我一直认为是种怪疾
I just assumed it was a zebra.
是乳腺癌
It's breast cancer.
乳腺癌怎么能用抗运动贴片治疗?
since when is breast cancer treatable,by motion sickness meds?
不能
It's not.
但是副肿瘤性症状引起的发炎,(恶性肿瘤对神经系统的远隔破坏)
But the inflammation caused,by the paraneoplastic syndrome
可由抗胆碱药控制
caused by the cancer can be reduced,by anticholinergics.
嗨 来
Hey,here you go.
他会死吗?
Is he gonna die?
我们在竭尽所能
We're doing all we can.
但还不知道他到底得了什么毛病
We don't know what's wrong with him yet.
我会死吗?
Am I gonna die?
不会的
No.
来 嚼这个
Here,chew on these.
好消息是飞行员吃的都是牛羊肉
Good news is,all the pilots are red meat men.
虽然我有点想去降落这架小飞机
Although I was kind of looking forward,to landing this puppy myself.
Peng的情况越来越糟
Peng's getting worse.
这说得通
That makes sense.
头等舱比经济舱先开膳
First class ate before coach.
他呕吐之前消化了更多东西
He digested more,of his food before he threw up.
也可能是你错了,神经学的症状很快就会出现
Or you're wrong and we're gonna start,seeing neurological symptoms soon.
癫痫 麻痹 共济失调
Seizures, paralysis, ataxia.
不会出现共济失调
We're not gonna see ataxia.
你就这么肯定自己是对的
You're so sure you're right.
不 他像婴儿般蜷缩呻吟着,怎么表现出行动不协调
No,it's just hard to show clumsiness,when you're lying moaning in the fetal position.
嗨!
Hey!
起...起来!
Sss-- stand up!
飞机上就没人会说韩语?
Nobody speak korean on this flight?
我以为你会
I assumed you did.
我知道怎么问他的妹妹是否满18岁
I know how to ask him,if his sister's over 18.
但这没用
I don't think that's gonna help.
嗨!
Hey!
起来!
Stand up!
起 来
Stand up.
别跟我装脚瘸
Don't play the cripple card with me.
我 潜
*******
哦 你好
Oh,hi.
我要走了
I'm leaving.
工作
Work.
哦 好吧
Oh,okay.
重要客户
Important client.
当然
Sure.
呃 听着...
Um,listen...
你们关系好吗?
are you close?
怎么?
Why?
她得做个乳房X光照片
She needs a mammogram.
噢 老天
Oh,god.
我知道我对你要求过多
I know I'm throwing a lot at you.
可她没有别的亲人在这儿
She just has no family in town.
她此刻真的需要朋友
And I really think,she could use a friend right now.
好了 把手放在这里
Okay,put your hand here.
你不用待在这里的
You don't have to stay.
不 这...
No,it'S...
没关系
no problem.
但是为什么?
But why?
你甚至不认识我
You don't even know me.
你肯定吓坏了
You gotta be scared.
我甚至希望是乳腺癌
I almost hope it's breast cancer.
不
No.
那样就不会是我的过错
Then it wouldn't be my fault.
不管是什么 都不是你的错
Whatever it is, it's not your fault.
不是那样
That's not true.
你可以控制一些事
You can control things.
虽不是全部
Not everything.
但可以不去招惹无谓的风险
But you don't have to take stupid risks.
我太傻了
I was being an idiot.
你只是找乐子
You were having fun.
你有过后悔的事吗?
You have regrets?
有啊
Yeah.
robin.
Robin
不要动
Hold still.
好
Good.
好了 再做一组
Okay, we're gonna get just one more.
抱歉 我知道很疼
Sorry, I know it hurts.
不是疼
It's not that.
是我的眼睛
It's my eye.
我的右眼 我...
My right eye, I--
我看不见了
I can't see.
肯定是共济失调
it's definitely ataxia.
肯定是皮疹
It's definitely a rash.
你要不要再看五分钟,然后下结论这也肯定是条腿?
You want to look at itfor five more minutes,before concluding it's also definitely a leg.
细腿
Thin leg.
打过石膏
It's been in a cast.
所以呢?
So?
可能是辐射中毒
So it could be radiation poisoning.
因为一条断腿?
From a broken leg?
因为他接受的x光
From the x-rays they took of it.
就算他全身骨头都断一次
He could break every bone in his body
接受的X光也不至于导致辐射疾病
and still not have enough x-rays,to cause radiation sickness.
除非那x光是由朝鲜的某个
Unless those x-rays,were performed in "wankoff",
赤脚医生用陈年老旧的机器照的
north korea by a third-grade,dropout with a 50-year-old imager.
也能说明他的秃顶
Which accounts for the absence of fur.
辐射中毒解释了所以症状
Radiation poisoning accounts for,all the symptoms.
我有头发
I have hair.
自从牙齿漂白后我就没拍过x光片
I haven't had an x-ray,since I got my teeth whitened.
你怀孕了
You're pregnant.
我什么了?
I'm what?
解释了晕机 腹部疼痛 发热
Explains the nausea, abdominal pains, fever.
也解释了为什么,你36C的胸塞在34B的胸罩里
And why you're stuffing your 36cs into a 34b bra.
- 那她的皮疹呢?,- 妊娠疹
- and her rash?,- Pupps.
在孕妇身上很常见
A common pregnancy rash.
我不可能怀孕
I can't be pregnant.
你是处女?
You a virgin?
- 不 但是...,- 你怀孕了
- No,but--,- you're pregnant.
恭喜(犹太用语)
Mazel tov.
把他抬到座位上去
Let's get him into the chair.
两种不同诊断
Two different diagnose
我以为你不相信巧合
I thought  you didn't believe,in coincidences.
我相信统计学
I believe in statistics.
飞机上200个乘客
200 passengers on the plane.
10个应该是同性恋
10 should be gay,
两个应该带着小孩
two should be with child,
有一个应该是基因突变的麻烦精
and one should be incredibly annoying,with an extra ass chromosome.
House.
House
给他点碘盐来保护甲状腺
Get him some iodized salt to protect his thyroid.
- 我要回去...,- House
- I'm going back--,- house.
你错了
You're wrong.
我就说我们该回头
I said we should've turned back.
你应该听我的
You should have listened to me.
现在我们在北极圈上空八英里...
Now we're eight miles over the arctic—
我正在试着听 所以闭嘴
I'm trying to listen to you now,,so shut up.
心脏没问题
Heart's fine.
胸部很坚挺
Breasts are firm.
有传染性吗?
is it contagious?
很多乘客吓坏了
A lot of the passengers are scared.
告诉他们没什么可担心的
Tell them there's nothing to worry about.
有什么要担心吗?
Is there something to worry about?
有
Yeah.
告诉他们没什么可担心的
Tell them there's nothingto worry about.
给我拿支手电
Get me a flash light.
用这个把左眼遮住
Cover your left eye with this.
恐光症!
Mm-- photophobia!
脑膜炎的症状
Symptom of meningitis.
我们需要抗生素
We need antibiotics.
我会联系药房的
I'll call down to the pharmacy.
你吓到我了
You're creeping me out.
那就给我间实验室
Then get me a lab.
假单胞菌闻起来像发酵
Pseudomonas smell yeasty.
葡萄球菌闻起来像发霉
Staph smells musty.
有些肝病闻起来像氨水
Some liver diseases smellof ammonia.
House 我没发烧
House,I'm not in heat.
鼻子上有柑橘芬香,烤椰香的腮红
Citrusy on the nose,,with a blush of toasted coconut.
我得仔细看看你的皮疹
I need to get a better look at your rash.
运用你的想象力
Use your imagination.
那我是该想像救生员Cuddy呢,还是修女院长Cuddy?
Fine,shall I gowith lifeguard cuddy,or mother superior cuddy?
又有三名乘客病了
Three more passengers are sick.
如果没有药
If we don't get drugs,
会死好多人了
we're gonna have a lot of dead passengers.
右眼失明表示这不是乳腺癌
Blindness in her right eye,indicates it's not breast cancer.
似乎是神经学上的问题
It's likely neurological.
我今天才遇见她
I just met her today.
你该走了
You should go.
她需要有人在这儿
She needs someone here.
你没有这义务
That's not your job.
请让我知道她没事
Please let me know that she's okay.
只是性
It's just sex.
没这回事
There's no such thing.
另一只眼
Other eye.
你是说女人不能把性和爱分开吗?
are you saying women can't separate,the physicalfrom the emotional?
没人能做得好
No one does it well.
女人做的尤其糟糕
Women do it worse.
你想我们停下 因为你觉得那影响到...
You just want us to stop,,because you thinkit's affecting--
我
me.
是的
Yeah.
多重棘波超过01和02
Polyspikes over 01 and 02.
那是她的左眼
That's her left eye.
全面脑电波爆发性抑制
Burst suppression on every lead.
Fran?
她昏迷了
She's comatose.
没有...
nothing...
Nothing...
拜托 不会没有人带药的
Come on,nody has no meds.
你干什么
Excuse me.
张开嘴
Open your mouth.
阿昔洛韦在哪? (治疗带状疱疹的药物)
Where is the acyclovir?
我没有服用药物
I'm not on any meds.
最好还是用一点
Well,you'd better get some.
你有疱疹
You've got herpes.
看到没有
Oh,what do you know?
他有一些
He's got some.
今天是你的幸运日
This must be your lucky day.
现在是来真的了
This is for real!
有人得病了
People are sick.
除非你们贡献一下,我们中的一些人会被装在裹尸袋里
Some of us will be deplaning in body,bags unless you cough up.
谢谢你...
Thank you...
谢谢你
thank you.
Thank you.
愿上帝保佑你
God bless you.
她的大脑因为颅内高压而停止运转
her brain is shutting down,because of intercranial pressure.
或许她的神经在死亡
Or her nerves are dying.
正因为不断增加的压力
Because of the increased pressure.
她的脑内出血了
She has a bleed in her brain.
- 你说过她的脑部CT,- 显示没有肿瘤
- You said the ct showed--,- no tumors.
但若是由于脑动静脉畸形导致脑出血
But if she has an avm,leading to a cerebral hemorrhage,
我们可能没注意到
we could have missed it.
需要颅穿孔来降压—
She needs a burr holeto relieve—
你想钻开她的脑袋 ,因为CT照不出来的无形出血?
you want to drill in her brain because of,an invisible bleed the ct couldn't see?
该做腰椎穿刺来确认是否有红细胞,(正常脑脊髓液中没有红细胞)
We should do an lp to confirm,the presence of red blood cells.
她大脑会脱形 然后她就死了
And her brain herniates and,then she dies.
是啊 不如在手术中弄死她
Right, better to kill herin the or.
Chase 你觉得呢?
Chase,what do you think?
这是个悬念
Here's a cliffhanger.
我想在凿开她大脑前,最好先弄清楚她得的是什么
I think it'd help to know what she has,before we start digging into her brain.
小心一点为妙
Might be betterto play it safe to start.
做腰椎穿刺
Do an lp.
你俩的性爱一定美妙极了
Sex better be damn good.
药物多多 管用的没几个
Lotta apples, not many candy bars.
有抗生素吗?
Any antibiotics?
3颗安美汀 (抗感染药)
Three caps of augmentin.
一共有6个病人
There are six patients.
都用在peng身上
Give them to peng.
他对青霉素过敏
He's allergic to penicillin.
医疗急救箱里有两支肾上腺素注射器
The first aid kit has two epi pens.
一旦他出现强烈反应
if he has a severe reaction,
十只肾上腺素都救不了他,你吃药
ten epi pens won't save him,,you take the pills.
他更糟
He's worse.
他连英语都不会讲
He's a guy who doesn't speak english.
让他服药
Give him the meds.
如果这不是脑膜炎
If it's not meningitis,
就等于拿他的生命冒险 而且浪费了药
we're risking his life,and flushing meds down the toilet.
给他做腰椎穿刺
Then do an lp on him.
如果脑脊液清澈 你赢
If it's clear,you win.
如果混浊
If it's cloudy,
给他用安美汀
he gets the augmentin and
冒过敏反应的危险
we risk a reaction.
计划听起来不错
Sounds like a plan.
可惜我们没有腰椎穿刺针
Oh,except for the part,where we don't have an lp needle.
还有这飞机摇摇晃晃
Oh,and the shaking of the plane means
我也许会刺穿他的脊髓 让他终身伤残
I'll probably pierce his spinal cord,and cripple him for life,
这计划确实听起来不错
but,i mean,,it totally sounds like a plan.
你是对的
You're right.
让他去死 把药给我
Let him die.Give me the meds.
有了
Got it.
不妙
Damn.
- 这是什么?,- 闭嘴
- What is it?,- Shut up.
别这么歇斯底里
Don't get hysterical.
告诉我到底怎么样
Just tell me what the hell it is.
House!
我们该调头的
We should have turned back.
我们早该调头的
We should have turned back!
House!
拿着这个
Hold this.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
有一名乘客被确诊为细菌性脑膜炎
we have a passenger with a confirmed,case of bacterial meningitis.
即使想办法尽快降落
And even if we land as soon as possible,
这名乘客也活不了
the passenger will not survive.
很有可能诸位也被感染了
It's very likely that some of you,have been infected as well.
所以一旦你们出现症状
As soon as you start feeling symptoms,
我们将隔离你们在头等舱
we need to isolate you,in the first class cabin.
症状包括发热 皮疹 晕吐
Fever, rash, nausea,
到晚期的话
and in the late stages...
左手颤动
tremor in the left hand.
我有症状
I have that.
噢 上帝啊
Oh, god.
不
No!
我们该怎么办?
What do we do?
开瓶香槟
Break out the bubbly.
嘿 认真听着
Yo! Listen up!
坏消息是你们确实得了病
Bad news is you have an illness.
好消息是并非脑膜炎
The good news is,it's not meningitis.
不致命
It's not fatal.
比较丢脸罢了
It's just embarrassing.
是转化症 (压力引起的假性神经学症状)
It's conversion disorder.
通俗点就是群体歇斯底里
Or commonly known as mass hysteria.
在高度不安的情况下时有发生,尤其是女性
It happens often in high anxiety,situations,especially to women.
这听起来有点性别歧视
I know it sounds sexist,
但科学认为你们虚弱不坚强 我又能怎样?
but science says you're weak and soft,,what can I do?
House 你错了
house, you're wrong.
看我的手
Look at my hand.
是啊 看她的手 颤抖的左手
Yeah,look at her hand.Shaking left hand.
那是什么症状 肯定不是脑膜炎
What is that a symptom of?,Not meningitis.
什么都说明不了的症状
It's basically a symptom of nothing.
把想法植入他们的大脑 坐着看好戏吧
put the idea into their heads,and watched it happen.
Peng同样将呕吐和皮疹也传达给你们
Same thing that peng cruelly did,with the puking and the rash.
皮疹是我想出来的?
The rash is in my head?
大脑控制着身体
Your mind controls your body.
倘若大脑觉得你病了 就会让你发病
It thinks you're sick,,it makes you sick.
如果大家好好冷静一下
If--if you'll all just calm down,
所有症状就会很快消失.
your symptoms will soon go away.
为了加快这个康复进程
And to facilitate this process,
机组人员会在机舱供应免费饮品
your flight crew will move through the cabin,with a complimentary bar service.
多谢 一如既往 祝您旅途愉快
Thank you and, as always,,have a pleasant flight.
- 还觉得想吐?,- 不
- Still feel like puking?,- No.
你怎么知道的?
How did you know?
腰穿结果阴性
Lp was negative.
我想到了另一个理论 测试了一下
I came up with an alternate theory,and I tested it.
没你还真不能成功
Couldn't have done it without you.
愤怒是群体歇斯底里的表现之一
Rage is a symptom of mass hysteria.
还有一件事要解决
Just one more thing to clean up.
Peng引发了群体歇斯底里
Peng set off the mass hysteria.
什么让peng发作?
What set off peng?
他真的快死了
He really is dying.
是 而我完全不知道为什么
Yeah. And I haven't the faintest idea why.
外延牧师行径是什么?
What's extension pastoring?
指你被牧师的堂兄性骚扰
It's when you're molested,by a priest's cousin.
我们真的需要这三个人在吗?
Do we really need these three?
怕被他们比下去?
Worried they'll make you look bad?
可能是脑损伤造成的症状
Could be symptomatic of head trauma.
脑梗塞 颅内出血 有什么想法?
Cerebral infarction or,intercranial hemorrhage.Thoughts?
什么时候才能降落?
How long till we land?
太久 等不了
Too long to wait.
他的头滑得像婴儿肚皮
His head's as smooth as a baby's bottom.
没有肿块 我想可以排除脑外伤
No bumps,so I think we,can rule out head trauma.
就在剩下的里面选吧
So you gotta choose between what's left.
阻塞还是渗漏?
Clog or a leak?
你在谈马桶吗?
you're talking of toilet?
House.
House
这样有帮助?
Is this actually helpful?
目前还没
Not so far.
会不会是梅毒?
What about syphilis?
首先 他说其他人都不懂的外语
First of all,he apparently speaks,a language that no one else speaks.
增加了挑逗女士的难度
Which makes talking up the,ladies a little rough.
我们是从新加坡起飞的
We're flying out of singapore.
只要有信用卡和避孕套 想要什么都行
If he has a credit card and a condom,,he can get anything he wants.
什么?
What?
避孕套
Condoms.
他有焦点性四肢瘫痪
He has focal limb paralysis.
避孕套造成他腿部瘫痪?
His legs got paralyzed by a condom?
不 是避孕套里的可卡因
No, by cocaine,that was inside the condom,
现在正弥散在他的消化系统
and is now spreading,through his digestive tract.
你觉得他是走私犯?,(避孕套包裹毒品 藏于体内)
You think he's a mule.
我觉得他是个蠢蛋
I think he's a jackass.
要动手术
We're gonna have to operate.
酷
Cool.
会弄死她的
They're gonna kill her.
我们都错了
We were wrong.
说明Foreman是对的
Which means Foreman was right.
也许Foreman对我们的看法也是对的
Maybe Foreman's right about us too.
也许我们该结束这一切
Maybe we should just stop all this.
如果这影响了工作
I mean, if it's affecting our jobs.
并没有影响到工作
It's not affecting our jobs.
我们在病人房间做爱
We had sex in a patient's bedroom.
在查找毒素的床上做爱
A bedroom we were examining for toxins.
是 我俩真是神志清醒
Yeah, our judgment's right on the mark.
好了 再也不在病人家里做爱
All right, no more sex at patient's homes.
也不在有猫看着的时候做
No more sex with cats watching.
还有什么要从做爱单上划掉的?
Anywhere else you want,to cross off the list?
- 那盆,- 什么?
- The bowl.,- What?
她来这儿以后吃过东西吗?
Has she eaten since she's been here?
她来了之后就一直病着
She's been sick since she's been here.
如果这就是一个症状呢?
What if it's a symptom?
- 为什么你会觉得--,- 这猫食盆是满的
- Why would you think--,- the bowl was full.
把他牢牢按住
you're gonna need to hold him down.
他会挣扎的
He's not gonna like this.
你真的认为他是毒贩?
Do you really think he's a mule?
这能解释所有的症状
It fits the symptoms.
你确定不会传染?
You sure he's not contagious?
基本上
Pretty much.
不要 基本上 确定
Can't be"pretty much" sure.
这表示你不确定
It means you're not sure.
噢 你好聪明
Oh, aren't you clever?
我知道你基本上没有知觉
Well,I know you're,"pretty much" unconscious,
但有人向我指出
but as it's been pointed out to me,
基本上并非十成把握
"pretty much" doesn't mean squat.
好了 牢牢抓好他
Okay, hold him tight.
做得快 能减少他休克死的几率
The faster we do this,,the less likely he is to die of shock.
再紧一点
Tighter.
- 抱歉,- 再来一次
- Sorry.,- Do that again.
放松 再压下去
Ease off, then press down.
在关节上加压 能缓解疼痛
Pressure on his joints,relieves his pain.
怎么了
Okay.
又错了
Wrong again.
他的钱包在哪里?
Where's his wallet?
危险: 经甲基溴熏蒸 72小时内不可进入
DANGER:PREMISES HAVE BEEN FUMIGATED WITH,METHYL BROMIDE NO ADMITTANCE FOR 72 HOURS
自携呼吸器潜水资历卡
Scuba certification card.
- 有什么了不起 我也有,- 是啊
- Big deal.I have one of these.,- Yeah.
你也有昨天在德光岛,自携呼吸器潜水的收据吗?
Do you alsohave a receipt from,tekong's scubarental dated yesterday?
叫机长尽量下降到5000英尺以下
Tell the captain to drop as,low as he can under 5,000 feet.
- 现在是38000英尺高 不能,- peng得的是潜水病
- We're at 38,000.We can't--,- peng's got the bends.
他昨天潜过水
He went diving yesterday,
由于蠢 他太快升上水面
and like an idiot,,he surfaced too quickly.
由于非常非常蠢
And like a bigger idiot,
他登上升至海平面上8000尺高的飞机
he boarded a flight which is pressurized,to 8,000 feet above sea level.
低气压让他生命垂危,(减压过急 本溶于血液的氮气形成气泡)
Low pressure is killing him.
让飞行员尽量下降,直到能将小海豹抡飞窗外
Tell the pilot to dive until we can,club baby seals out of the window.
给他吸氧
And get him some oxygen.
50年前 这是一幢整体的房子
Fifty years ago,it was one estate.
两家共用一个电气系统
The two homes shared an electrical system.
不幸的是除虫工人不知道
Unfortunately the exterminator,didn't know that,
所以隔壁熏虫的时候
so when they fumigated next door,
有毒气体顺着旧管道 到了你的房子里
the poison gas flowed through,the old pipe and into your house.
东莨菪碱贴片掩盖了毒性
the scopolamine patch was,masking the effects of the poison.
你需要留院观察几天
You'll have to stay here,for a few more days,
之后应该就没什么事了
but after that you should be fine.
很遗憾 你的猫死了
I'm sorry about your cat.
抱歉你的头发
And your hair.
12年了Harrington没离开过屋子
For 12 years,,harrington never left the property.
我以为这是对我离开的惩罚
I thought I was being,punished for going away,but
原来是...
really...
对我回家的惩罚
I was being punished for coming home.
谢谢
Thank you.
我救了你一命 你欠我的
I saved your life.You owe me.
我没病
I wasn't sick.
但你原本不知道 你欠我的
But you didn't know that.,You owe me.
我现在知道了
I know it now.
你的大脑唆使身体出现皮疹 畏光和呕吐
Your mind convinced your body to,get a rash,photophobia,and vomit.
也许接着就会让你冷冰冰的心停止跳动
How do you know it wouldn't have,shut down your cold,cold heart next?
我不欠你什么
I don't owe you.
你好贱
You're mean.
能弥补我的虚弱
That's how I compensate for being weak...
不坚强
and soft.
我想跟你说声谢谢
I just wanted to say thank you.
超级不用谢
you're extremely welcome.
还有 我每个星期一都在纽约
And I'm in new york every monday.
残疾人可以畅达你吗?
Are you handicap accessible?
*你眉头紧锁*
*Stitch in your knitted brow*
*不知为何*
*and you don't know how*
好啊 Robin?
hi, robin?
这是Wilson Fran的医生
This is, um, uh,,dr. Wilson, f-Fran's doctor.
James.
是中毒
It was a toxin.
发现得及时 她会好起来的
We caught it on time,and she's gonna be fine.
是 会的
Yeah, it is.
你会不会来探望她
listen, I was just wondering if,you were coming back in again to visit.
- 干得漂亮,- 谢了
- Nice catch.,- Thanks.
连House都会觉得高明
Think even house would be impressed.
那我可说不准
I don't know about that.
想怎么庆祝
Any idea how you want to celebrate?
什么?
What?
我想要更多
I want more.
我还觉得你有点精疲力尽了  但--
I thought you were getting a,little worn out, but--
我不是这个意思
that's not what I meant.
我知道
I know.
只是希望你能明白我的暗示,假装没说过这话
I was just hoping you'd take the hint,and pretend you never said that.
比起现在我想要更多
I want this to be more than it is.
我以为我们讲清楚的
I thought we were clear.
一开始是 难道你敢说
In the beginning,,but you can't tell me you--
是的 我敢
yes, I can.
我没有
And I don'T.
只是开心 仅此而已
It was.Fun.That's it.
现在都结束了
And now it's over.